carnegiehall.org 2019-10-04

# Privacy Policy | Carnegie Hall

This Website Privacy and Cookie Policy (“ ** _Privacy Policy_** ”) was last updated as of May 24, 2018. 

Protecting your personal information is our priority. This Privacy Policy describes how the nonprofit The Carnegie Hall Corporation (“ _ **Carnegie Hall**_ ,” “ _ **we**_ ,” “ _ **our**_ ” _or_ “ _ **us**_ ”) collects, uses, and shares personal and non-personal information when you visit the carnegiehall.org website, when you receive e-mails sent by Carnegie Hall and when you use Carnegie Hall online products. 

This Privacy Policy applies when you use the Carnegie Hall website, opt in to Carnegie Hall e-mails or use other Carnegie Hall online products. 

This Privacy Policy was last updated as of the date above, and we recommend that you check this Privacy Policy regularly for any relevant updates. We will notify you of important updates by e-mail, to the extent we have your e-mail address, or other appropriate means. 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any websites other than carnegiehall.org or online products that are not Carnegie Hall’s, including websites to which you may link from carnegiehall.org (e.g., Facebook, Twitter, and YouTube), e-mails that are not sent by Carnegie Hall, and online products other than those of Carnegie Hall. 

You are not required to provide the information described below. If you decide not to provide any of this information, you may be unable to access certain options, offers and services that involve our interaction with you. 

##### I. INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT

We collect personal and non-personal information to provide better services to our stakeholders. 

**A. Personal Information**

_**1\. Types of Personal Information Collected and When**_

_a. Collected From You_

We may gather personal information that you give us, including your name, address, phone number, e-mail address and payment details. 

For example, we collect personal information **on our website** when you: 

  * Create an account 
  * Purchase tickets 
  * Purchase a membership 
  * Purchase merchandise 
  * Purchase a gift card 
  * Make a donation 
  * Fill out a “Keep Up To Date” form 
  * Fill out a “Contact Us” request 
  * Enter a contest or sweepstake 
  * Contact customer support 
  * Participate in certain education programs of the Weill Music Institute (WMI) (e.g., when you complete an online application) 

In addition, we may collect personal information **outside our website** via:

  * Phone sales (CarnegieCharge for single tickets, memberships and gift certificates; telemarketing for subscriptions; and telefunding for memberships and donations) 
  * Group sales (generally by phone or e-mail form following direct contact with a ticketing representative) 
  * In person (Box Office walk-ups) 
  * On-Site (during an event, a customer may choose to complete a form and hand it to a staff member, for example in connection with membership or subscription) 
  * Returning mail subscription order forms 
  * Completing contact information on forms at neighborhood concerts and similar events 

_b. Collected from Third Parties or Other Sources_

If we collect personal information directly from you, we may use it alone or in combination with information we acquire about you from third parties, or that is publicly available from other sources, in order to better tailor and personalize our offerings and our communications with you. Your information may be shared with us by independent organizations, e.g., other performance venues, arts organizations with which we work, third-party ticket vendors, applications providers and survey providers. These organizations should only share your personal information with us when it is required to complete a contract or you have consented. You should check such third-parties’ privacy policies for further information. 

_**2\. Where We Store and Process Your Personal Information**_

We may collect and store information (including personal and non-personal information) locally on your device and within your web browser application. We may also store such information in our databases. 

We are a nonprofit, mission-driven organization headquartered in New York City, and your personal information may be stored and processed outside of your country of residence. The personal information we collect is processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the applicable law, wherever your information is located. As a best practice, we have networks, databases, servers, systems and support located in various U.S. states, and we may work together with third parties around the world (see “ **Sharing Information with Certain Third Parties** ” for further details). 

For further information on international transfers of your personal information outside of the European Economic Area (the “EEA”) **for individual communications originating in the EEA, please see below**. 

**_3\. Retention of Your Personal Information_**

We will retain your personal information for as long as we reasonably require it for legal or business purposes. This period will be determined on the basis of applicable legal requirements and business purposes. When such period ends or we no longer need your personal information, we will securely delete or destroy it. 

Information we collect when you are signed in to the Carnegie Hall website, in addition to information we obtain about you from third parties, may be associated with your Carnegie Hall account. When information is associated with your Carnegie Hall account, we treat it as personal information. 

_**4\. Access to and Managing your Personal Information**_

You have the right to request access to and manage the personal information relating to you that we store and process: 

  * **Access:** Upon your request, we will respond to you promptly and provide you with access to personal information we have collected from you. 
  * **Correction:** You can help Carnegie Hall maintain the accuracy of your personal information by notifying us when you change your address, phone number or e-mail address, or if you think that any other personal information we hold about you is inaccurate or needs to be updated. 
  * **Deletion:** You may request that we delete your personal information. Further information about your grounds for deletion can be found at [ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/media/for-organisations/documents/1475/deleting_personal_data.pdf). However, deletion of your personal information may not always be possible due to legal obligations and other factors. 
  * **Restricting our Use:** You may request that we stop processing your personal information (other than storing it), if: (a) you contest the accuracy of it (unless the accuracy is verified); (b) you believe the processing is against the law; (c) you believe that we no longer need your information for the purposes for which it was collected, but you still need your personal information to establish or defend a legal claim; or (d) you object to the processing, and we are verifying whether our legitimate grounds to process your personal information override your own rights. 
  * **Object:** You have the right to object to processing, including: (a) for direct marketing; (b) for research or statistical purposes; or (c) where processing is based on legitimate interests. 
  * **Portability:** If you wish to transfer your information to another organization as data controller (and certain conditions are satisfied), you may ask us to do so, and we will send it directly if we have the technical means. 
  * **Right to Withdraw Consent:** If you previously gave us your consent (by a clear affirmative action) to allow us to process your personal information for a particular purpose, but you no longer wish to consent to us doing so, you may contact us to let us know that you withdraw that consent. If you do not do so, we may continue to rely upon that previous consent to keep using and processing your personal information in the same way. 

**B. Non-Personal Information**

We collect information to provide better services to our stakeholders. When you visit the carnegiehall.org website, we collect device-specific information such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, hardware model, operating system version and mobile network information. In addition, we gather information about the type of browser you are using (including the specific version), and from which website you came. 

We use various technologies to collect and store information when you visit carnegiehall.org, use our online products or receive one of our e-mails. For example, we use cookies and web beacons to collect information, store your online preferences, and automatically recognize you when you return to our website. Please **see below for further information on our use of cookies**. 

##### II. USING THE INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT

**A. Operation of Our Business and Website and to Perform a Contract with You**

Carnegie Hall uses the information we collect from and about you in connection with the operation of our business and nonprofit mission, and to carry out a contract with you (for example, to communicate with you regarding events to which you have purchased tickets), and to offer an enhanced, personalized online experience on our website and online products. 

The information we collect allows us to: 

  * Recognize you when you return to our website so we can personalize your experience 
  * Process applications and transactions 
  * Respond to your requests 
  * Solve any issues you might be facing (and keep a record for so long as is necessary to solve such issues) 

**B. Where We Have Your Consent**

  * Provide you with relevant offers on our website and online products and in e-mail promotions. 
  * Inform you about our services, such as letting you know about upcoming changes or improvements. 
  * Use information collected from cookies or web beacons to improve your user experience and the overall quality of our services. 

**C. Where We Have Justifiable Reason (including a Legitimate Interest)**

  * Help us target our marketing and communications so that they’re more relevant to you. 
  * Contact you to ask you to participate in consumer research. 

**D. Sharing Information with Certain Third Parties**

With the exceptions described below, we will not share personal information about you with any other entity. 

_**1\. Our Service Providers**_

We provide your information to trusted third-party companies to perform services on our behalf, including payment processing, data analysis, e-mail delivery, hosting services, customer service, and to assist in our marketing efforts. We direct all such third-party service providers to maintain the confidentiality of the information disclosed to them and not to use your information for any purpose other than to provide services on Carnegie Hall’s behalf. 

_**2\. Organizers of Concerts and Special Events at Carnegie Hall**_

We share personal information that you give us with third-party organizers of concerts and special events at Carnegie Hall for their direct-marketing purposes, but only if you purchase tickets to their concerts and events, and have opted in to such communications. 

_**3\. Purposes of Safety, Security, and Compliance with the Law**_

Your information and the contents of your private online communications may be accessed and disclosed (a) in response to legal process (for example, a court order, search warrant, or subpoena); (b) when we have a good-faith belief that we are required to disclose the information in response to legal process; (c) in other circumstances in which Carnegie Hall believes the carnegiehall.org website or a Carnegie Hall online product is being used in the commission of a crime (including exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit-risk reduction); (d) when we have a good-faith belief that there is an emergency that poses a threat to the safety of you or another person; and (e) when necessary to protect the rights or property of Carnegie Hall, including to enforce the Terms and Conditions of our website or to render the service you have requested. 

_**4\. Contest Sponsors**_

We may occasionally present a special contest, sweepstake or other promotion on the carnegiehall.org website, and the promotion may be sponsored by a third party. To qualify for entry, we may ask you to provide personal information. If we plan to share the personal information we request from you with the promotion’s sponsor, we will notify you at the point at which the information is collected, such as in the promotion’s official rules. 

_**5\. In Connection With a Sale or Merger**_

In the event that Carnegie Hall undergoes a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another organization, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, we may transfer all of your information, including personal information, to the successor organization in such transition. If material changes to our privacy practices will occur as a result of the business transition, we will notify you of the business transition prior to transferring your personal information. 

**E. Transfers Outside of the EEA**

If originating in the EEA, we may transfer your personal information outside of the EEA to Carnegie Hall in the United States for the purpose of providing services to you and promoting our nonprofit mission. If the United States does not offer the same level of data protection as your country of residence in the EEA, we take measures to ensure an appropriate level of protection for your personal information. 

We may also make similar transfers outside of the EEA where you have explicitly consented or where we consider this to be necessary for: (i) us to perform the contract with you; (ii) us to perform a contract with another party, which was made in your interests; or (iii) important reasons of public interest or to establish exercise of defend legal claims. 

##### III. CHILDREN

We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13. Any portion of the carnegiehall.org website intended for children under 13 will not request any personal information. Children under 13 should not provide any personal information to Carnegie Hall. In the event that we learn that we have inadvertently gathered personal information from children under 13, we will take reasonable measures to promptly erase such information from our records.

##### IV. CONTACT INFORMATION

To access or update your information, or to stop receiving communications from Carnegie Hall (as data controller), please contact Carnegie Hall by e-mail at [feedback@carnegiehall.org](mailto:feedback@carnegiehall.org) or by postal mail at the following address: 

Carnegie Hall  
881 Seventh Avenue  
New York, NY 10019  
Attn: Web Development 

You can also sign in to your online Carnegie Hall account at carnegiehall.org to access and change your personal information. Once you have reached your account page, click on “Edit Profile” to access your name, address, and contact information; click on “Preferences” under “Email Preferences” to manage your Carnegie Hall e-mail subscriptions. 

If you contact us in writing, please include your old and new contact information so that we can make the appropriate corrections. Please note that, in order to verify that we are communicating with you or someone authorized to act on your behalf, we may make access to your personal information conditional on the verification of certain information previously provided by you. 

##### V. YOUR RIGHT TO COMPLAIN

If you have provided personal information from within the EU, and you feel that we have not resolved your complaint to your satisfaction and you wish to make a formal complaint to the relevant national data protection authority in the EU, you can find the relevant details at [ec.europa.eu](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080). 

##### VI. USE OF COOKIES

Our website and online products use cookies to distinguish you from other users, provide a better experience when you browse our sites, and make interactions with our sites faster, more useful and more secure. By continuing to browse our sites, you are agreeing to our use of cookies. 

A cookie is a small data file that websites can place on your device when you visit. Cookies were designed to be a reliable mechanism for websites to remember stateful information (such as items added in the shopping cart) or to record the user’s browsing activity (including clicking particular buttons, logging in, or recording which pages you visited in the past). 

**A. How We Use Cookies**

  * **Authentication:** If you’re signed in, cookies help us show you the right information and personalize your experience. Cookies enable us to identify your device, secure your access to carnegiehall.org and our sites generally, and even help us know if someone attempts to access your account from a different device. 
  * **Preferences, Features and Services:** Cookies can remember your preferences and give you a personalized experience that’s in line with your settings. For example, they can help you fill out forms more easily. They also help us provide you with features, insights, and customized content. 
  * **Advertising:** Cookies help us serve relevant ads to you while browsing other websites. We may also use a cookie to learn whether someone saw an ad on the advertiser’s site and later visited carnegiehall.org and took an action (e.g., made a purchase). 
  * **Performance, Analytics and Research:** Cookies help us learn how well our sites performs in different locations. We also use cookies to understand, improve, and research products, features, and services, including when you access our sites from other websites, applications, or devices such as your work computer or your mobile device.

**B. Types of Cookies We Use**

We use two types of cookies: persistent and session. A persistent cookie helps us recognize you as an existing user, so it’s easier to return to our site. After you sign in, a persistent cookie stays in your browser and will be read by carnegiehall.org or our other online products when you return to the site. Session cookies only last for as long as the session (usually the current visit to a website or a browser session). 

**C. Third Party Cookies**

In addition to cookies that we use on our website or other online products, third parties may set cookies when you visit our website or online products. Third party cookies originate from a domain that is different from the domain of the website you’re visiting. Your browser will connect to the third party’s web servers to retrieve the content and they are able to set or read their own cookies on your device. We don’t control how third parties use their cookies, so we recommend that you check each of their cookie policies to see how they’re using them and how you can manage them. 

**D. How You Can Control Cookies**

Most browsers allow you to control cookies through their settings preferences. However, if you limit the ability of websites to set cookies, you may worsen your overall user experience, since it will no longer be personalized to you. 

Where cookies are not necessary for us to provide the services you have requested, we will ask you to consent to their use when you first visit our site. If you wish to manage the cookies we use, you can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, which lets you choose whether or not to accept it, or set your browser to accept any cookies automatically. Please note that, if you decide not to allow certain cookies, some features and services on our sites may not work properly because we may not be able to recognize you. For more information about cookies, including how to set your browser to reject cookies, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

##### VII. PROMOTIONAL E-MAILS

You may wish to create a Carnegie Hall account to enrich your relationship with us. An account is created when purchasing subscriptions, single tickets and memberships. An account is also created when you make a donation, or you create an account to access news and information about upcoming concerts and educational programs. When creating a Carnegie Hall account, you will be given the opportunity to opt in to receive promotional e-mails, customer service notifications, newsletters and other information from Carnegie Hall. If you choose to opt in, you can later choose to opt out of receiving additional promotional e-mails from Carnegie Hall by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in any such e-mail, or by submitting such a request by e-mail at [feedback@carnegiehall.org](mailto:feedback@carnegiehall.org) or by postal mail at the following address: 

Carnegie Hall  
881 Seventh Avenue  
New York, NY 10019  
Attn: Web Development 

You can also sign in to your online account on carnegiehall.org to opt-in or subsequently opt out of some or all of your e-mail subscriptions. 

Please note that, once we receive your request, it may take an additional period of time for your subsequent opt-out to become effective. Your unsubscribe or e-mail preference change will be processed promptly, within 10 business days. 

Note that if you choose not to opt in to receiving our promotional communications, we may still e-mail or communicate with you from time to time if we need to provide you with information or if we need to request information from you with respect to a transaction initiated by you or for other legitimate non-marketing reasons. 

##### VIII. SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using secure sockets layer (sometimes referred to as “SSL”) software that encrypts information you input. You can further help to ensure your security by taking a few simple precautions. For instance, you should protect against unauthorized access to your Carnegie Hall account username and password, and to your computer. You should also be sure to sign off when you have finished using a shared computer. 

If you make a purchase through the carnegiehall.org website, we will use your credit card number only to process your payment and will not use it for marketing purposes. For reasons of security, credit card information is not stored on our servers. We will retain purchase information for our records, and only share with third parties as provided in this Privacy Policy. 

We employ technical and physical safeguards to help prevent unauthorized access to user information that we maintain. Since no safeguards are one hundred percent secure, we cannot guarantee that our safeguards will prevent every unauthorized attempt to access, use or disclose personal information. Please notify us if you become aware of any issues. 

##### IX. DO NOT TRACK (DNT) SIGNAL COMPLIANCE

Do Not Track (DNT) is a concept that has been promoted by regulatory agencies such as the U.S. Federal Trade Commission for the Internet industry to develop and implement a mechanism for allowing Internet users to control the tracking of their online activities across websites by using browser settings. The World Wide Web Consortium has been working with industry groups, Internet browsers, technology companies, and regulators to develop a DNT technology standard. 

Our website does not follow Do Not Track settings in your browser because we use third-party services to conduct certain activities, such as Google Analytics, Google AdSense and Canopy Labs, which do not follow DNT settings. 

##### X. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time, and use of personal information that we gather is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of use. This Privacy Policy was last updated as of the **date above** , and we recommend that you check this Privacy Policy regularly for any relevant updates. We will notify you of important updates by e-mail, to the extent we have your e-mail address, or other appropriate means.
